# اطلاعات شخصي

متولد: ۱۳۶۹

محل سكونت: قم

#### اطلاعات تماس

09306756076 - 09052401067

rhnm.zahra@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/zahrarahnama

https://github.com/rahnamazahra

# زهرا رهنما

برنامه نویس بک اند لاراول

# خلاصه حرفه ای

توسعهدهندهی بکاند با ۳ سال تجربه در Laravel

آشنا به معماری تمیز و تست نویسی

اصول SOLID،

توسعه مبتنی بر DDD.

مسئولیتپذیر، منعطف در یادگیری،

علاقهمند به رشد فردی و تیمی.

تجربه در فریلنس و کار تیمی،

آشنا به داکر

در مسیر تبدیل شدن به توسعهدهندهی فولاستک(در حال یادگیری - React Next.js )

# سوابق شغلى

# شرکت داتیس , قم

1402 -1401

آغاز توسعه با فریمورک Laravel در معماری MVC و طراحی زیرساخت اولیه پروژه

پیادهسازی پنل مدیریت شامل طراحی فرانتاند (با Blade) و بکاند با Laravel

تحلیل و طراحی پایگاه داده با توجه به نیازهای پروژه و اجرای آن با MySQL

همکاری مؤثر در تیم برای ایجاد ساختاری قابل توسعه در بکاند

مشارکت در استقرار پروژه و مدیریت تغییرات نسخهها با Git

## استارتاپ جرنی , قم

- 1403 1402
- لیسانس مهندسی نرمافزار دانشگاه فنی قم • کادانی موندسی نیمافزار – دانشگاه دکت
- کاردانی مهندسی نرمافزار دانشگاه دکتر شریعتی تهران (رتبه 17 کشوری ورودی 1392)

## علايق شخصى

تحصيلات

- مجسمهسازی و دکوراسیون داخلی
- مطالعه کتابهای حوزهی رشد فردی
  - پیادهروی و طبیعتگردی
- علاقهمند به فیلمهای بیوگرافی و کارآفرینی
  - عکاسی و تدوین

## تجربهی کار داوطلبانه

**م**شارکت در فعالیتهای داوطلبانه با رویکرد کمکرسانی. لذت از کمک کردن و تأثیرگذاری اجتماع

توسعه APIهای امن و مستند با استفاده از Laravel و مستندسازی آنها با Swagger

پیادهسازی SSO (Single Sign-On) و ورود سازمانی برای کاربران سازمانهای طرف قرارداد

استفاده از Git Flow برای مدیریت گردش کار تیم توسعه و مشارکت مؤثر در Pull Requestها

انجام تستنویسی برای کدهای بکاند بهمنظور افزایش پایداری و جلوگیری از بروز یاگ

مانیتورینگ دقیق پروژه با استفاده از Laravel Pulse و Sentry برای ثبت و بررسی خطاها

پیاده سازی کیف پول و پرداخت با زرین پال

مشارکت در تحلیل و طراحی پایگاه داده متناسب با نیازهای پروژه و ساختار اطلاعات

پیادهسازی مکانیزم Webhook برای اتصال با سامانههای بیرونی (ارسال لینک به سازمان برای دریافت دیتا)

افزایش سطح امنیت و کنترل در بستر Aarvan Cloud برای جلوگیری از دانلود مستقیم ویدیوها

#### مدیران توسعه , مشهد

1404 - 1403

بهینهسازی عملکرد APIها و ساختار کد با رعایت اصول SOLID و Clean Code

طراحی و توسعه ساختار **قابلتوسعه و مقیاسپذیر** با استفاده از الگوی **Repository-Service Pattern** 

استفاده از **Linting Tools** برای جلوگیری از بروز خطاهای رایج در زمان توسعه و بهبود کیفیت کد

مستندسازی دقیق APIها با **Swagger YAML Files** جهت ارائه ساختاریافته و مستقل از کد

انجام **Refactor** برای بهینهسازی و سادهسازی منطق پروژه با رعایت اصول SOLID

استفاده از صف و جاب

پیاده سازی سرویس ورک فلو

تقویت نگهداریپذیری کد و سهولت توسعه توسط سایر اعضای تیم

# Zahra Rahnama

**Back-End Developer (Laravel)** 

# **Professional Summary**

Back-end developer with 3 years of experience in Laravel. Familiar with Clean Architecture, Test-Driven Development (TDD), and SOLID principles.

Skilled in Domain-Driven Design (DDD) and modern backend patterns. Responsible, adaptable, and committed to continuous learning and team growth.

Experienced in both freelancing and collaborative team environments. Currently transitioning into a full-stack developer (learning React & Next.js).

# **Work Experience**

Datis Company — *Qom* 

**Back-End Developer** 

2022 - 2023 (1401 - 1402)

- Initiated development using the Laravel framework based on the MVC architecture.
- Built an admin panel with Laravel and Blade, handling both front-end and back-end implementation.
- Designed and implemented MySQL database structures tailored to project requirements.
- Contributed to building a scalable and maintainable back-end system.
- Assisted in deployment and managed version control using Git.

## **Personal Information**

**Date of Birth:** 1990 **Location:** Qom, Iran

### **Contact**

**Q** 09306756076 | 09052401067

**⊗** <u>LinkedIn</u>

**GitHub** 

## Journey Startup — Qom

#### Back-End Developer

2023 - 2024 (1402 - 1403)

- Developed secure and well-documented RESTful APIs using Laravel and Swagger.
- Implemented SSO (Single Sign-On) and enterprise login systems for client organizations.
- Applied Git Flow for structured version control and participated actively in code reviews and pull requests.
- Wrote automated tests to ensure code stability and reduce bugs.
- Monitored application health and errors using Laravel Pulse and Sentry.
- Integrated **Zarinpal** for wallet and payment gateway functionality.
- Participated in database analysis and design based on project-specific needs.
- Implemented Webhook mechanisms to allow external systems to retrieve data via secure URLs.
- Improved video content security and download protection using Aarvan Cloud configurations.

#### Modiran Tose'e — Mashhad

#### Back-End Developer

2024 - Present (1403 - 1404)

- Optimized API performance and code quality following SOLID and Clean Code principles.
- Designed a scalable architecture using the Repository-Service
  Pattern.
- Applied **linting tools** to catch and prevent common coding issues during development.
- Documented APIs using Swagger YAML files for independent,

## **Education**

Bachelor's Degree in Software Engineering, Qom Technical University

Associate Degree in Software Engineering, Dr. Shariati University of Tehran Ranked 17th nationally among 2013 entrants

## **Personal Interests**

Sculpture and interior decoration

Reading personal development books

Walking and nature exploration

Interested in biographical and entrepreneurship movies

Photography and video editing

# **Volunteer Experience**

Active participation in volunteer activities with a strong passion for helping others and making a social impact.

structured technical documentation.

- Refactored code for simplified logic and maintainability.
- Implemented **Job and Queue systems** to manage asynchronous tasks.
- Built a **Workflow Service** to streamline internal business logic and processes.
- Ensured maintainability and ease of collaboration through clean, extensible codebases.